Have you ever taken a trade in the
markets where you have studied it for
hours, done top-down analysis, calculate
your entry points precisely, your take
profit, your stop loss, perfect entry
signal, and as soon as you enter the
position, it goes straight to your stop
loss, takes you out, and then it goes
straight to your take profit? Well,
we've all been there. I've been there
hundreds of times, if not thousands, and
all of that is because of liquidity. And
in today's video, I'm going to educate
you how to best possibly avoid that and
get educated on how liquidity works at
these precise entry points. So, first
things first, what is liquidity and why
is it responsible for wicking you out of
your trade and then going straight to
take profit? Is it because the banks and
the institutions are watching your stop
loss? Is it because your stop loss is
too tight? Is it just because the
liquidity is low or high at that very
point? Well, first things first,
liquidity is exactly what it means. It's
how liquid is the market at that very
point. The perfect example for liquidity
and exactly for you to understand
exactly what it is, it's like Ethereum,
for example, right? Ethereum, when
Ethereum was reaching the 5,000 mark
point for Ethereum, there was a lot of
sellers that wanted to get out at that
round psychological 5,000. So, people
started placing their take profits at
4,999,
4,998,
4,997.
So, there's a lot of liquidity, a lot of
exit points at that high. So, when the
market reaches that point, you're going
to have a lot of selling off happening
in the market, so the market starts
having pushes to the downside. Now, that
is exactly why Ethereum did not make it
all the way to 5,000 because everybody
was placing their take profits and their
executions to get out and they're
liquidating their positions right before
5,000 because they know a lot of people
wanted to get out at that high point.
So,
there's many points in the market where
there is liquidity, whether it's a
currency pair that's at an all-time low,
all-time high, in the middle of the
market, cryptocurrencies, uh stock
markets, every single parts of any
market, there is liquidity because you
need for there to be a buyer on one side
and there needs to be a seller on the
other side. What drives the market up is
people buying the market. What drives
the market down is people selling the
market. There's just simple supply and
demand and that is how the market will
always move. But it is very predictable
where these market moves happen, where
there's the most amount of liquidity.
There's points where market just passes
right through and there's points where
the market has a lot of struggle to
break through because there's a a lot of
people liquidating their positions at
that specific point. So, liquidity is
nothing other than people buying and
selling the market at that specific
point. But it's very predictable where
they can sell and where you can get
liquidated if you know how to read it
correctly, which I'll break down right
now. So, diving into the markets, let's
find out exactly where liquidity lies.
Is liquidity at a high point? Is it at a
low point? Is it in the middle? Where is
it? Well, technically, liquidity is at
every single point. When you have a
market that is moving to the upside,
there's liquidity that is driving price
to the upside. This is known as supply
and demand, buyers, support and
resistance, whatever the case is.
There's a lot of buying power. Now,
whenever this market has had a higher
high push, the market needs a bit of a
retracement to continue going to the
upside. So, this means that at one point
in time, the sellers were being stronger
than the buyers. Probably the same
people that drove the market up after
they've made money on this push up, they
start liquidating their positions and
that liquidation of their positions
starts driving price back down. When
price gets driven back down, they see it
at a discounted rate, they just made
money on this push, then they end up
buying again and then it ends up pushing
this to the upside. So, you can have
liquidity really be anywhere in the
market. It could be at a high point, it
could be on a retracement point, it
could be at a low point, it be on a
retracement point to continue to go to
the downside. Really could be anywhere,
but the most places where the majority
of liquidity is at is where there is a
consistent amount of rejection. So, for
example, if I were to show you this
market right here that I'm just drawing
up just randomly here, this market right
here, it'd be very predictable that
there's a lot of liquidity at this
specific zone right here. As you can
tell, whenever price gets here, the
liquidations come in and the market gets
driven down. The market gets liquidated,
gets driven down. When we're above it,
price gets pushed to the upside. When
it's below, it gets pushed to the
downside, to the downside. And now that
we're above it, it's pretty predictable
based off of what we are seeing to the
left that this market could continuously
get pushed to the upside. So,
this liquidation zone is also known as
support or resistance, supply and
demand, order block, area of interest,
anything that you want to call it. This
is where there's a lot of liquidity in
the market because it is very
predictable based off of how the buyers
and the sellers are reacting at this
specific point. If we are above this
zone specifically, you want to make sure
you're buying because that's where the
buyers are coming in. So, there's zones
like these where they're very liquid and
there's a lot of action coming into the
market. Compared to this zone right
here, it's
could be a possibility that sellers can
come into the market right now because
last time we were here, there was a
sell-off from this area. So, there could
be a lot of liquidity that comes into
the market and pushes price to the
downside. But, that's really only
happened one time. And this also has
great significance depending on what
time frame you're on. The higher the
time frame, the stronger the rejection,
the more liquidation that comes in for
longer periods of time, and they're a
lot stronger. So, I personally like to
look for liquidity zones, areas of
interest, support or resistance on the
higher time frames, and I like to look
for multiple taps. It could be more than
three taps is the most ideal.
Now, something like this that has one
rejection, one liquidation from this
area
could mean that there could be another
liquidation, but it's not as predictable
as if it were to be a zone like this
one. Because this zone obviously has a
lot more seller sellers below below it,
buyers when we're above it. So, this is
how you identify a specific zone of
liquidation in the market. An example of
a real position that I'm actually in
right now in the market is AUDCHF. This
market, on the weekly time frame,
there's a lot of buyers that come into
this market whenever we're above this
support, whenever we're above, whenever
we're above, buyers just always drive
price up when we're in the market. Now,
this right here is what many would call
a liquidity sweep, a fake out, an
institutional grab,
uh
in
you know, the the banks are taking out
the retail stop losses. And to me, I've
been trading for the last 7 years, 7 and
1/2 years now, it really is almost a big
hoax. It's almost like the aliens,
right? Like aliens are real or we
believe them to be real, but nobody's
really encountered one of them, or at
least it hasn't become super mainstream
that aliens are real, and it's not where
you get to engage with one every single
day. So, you can hear about it, you can
potentially believe in it, but there's
no like real hardcore evidence that
there is an alien. Right? There is no
real hardcore evidence that this is a
bank or an institution that has
liquidated your position. In my personal
humble opinion, it does not make any
sense why an institution would move
trillions of dollars to liquidate the
retail trader stop losses that only make
up 3% of the market.
Retail traders move the least amount of
money in the market every single day.
So, it doesn't make sense that the banks
and institutions are fishing for those
profits in a way.
It just doesn't logically make any sense
to me, and there's no real evidence of
it. People have said it for many years,
but there's no hardcore evidence like
this is proof that the banks are after
the retail trader stop losses.
I feel like this is a narrative that has
been created amongst retail traders when
they enter these losing streaks and they
want to put the blame on something other
than themselves or just the market doing
whatever the market does. So, this right
here there was a lot of liquidity. This
right here is not a liquidity sweep. And
I'm going to get later into this video
how you can potentially avoid these and
if anything use these in your favor. But
this zone right here has loads of
liquidity. Buying power when you're
above. When you're below, all the
liquidity is selling to the downside.
All the liquidity here is now going to
potentially sell to the downside. All
I'm doing is just doing what the
market's done before.
So, I'm in this position right now. I'm
looking for big-time sells to the
downside simply based off of this exact
same theory. Looking for liquidity. And
now here, this is where this could be
the liquidity sweep, liquidity grab,
things of the theories that behind that
and I'll break that down in just a
second. So, I've just showed you an
example of a current position that I am
in as of right now entering a trade
technically after the liquidity sweep.
So, I'm about to break down to you guys
how you can use this liquidity sweep and
this anticipation in your favor to
either enter a position right now. Now,
I want to be extremely clear.
Anybody that tells you out there that
they have a specific strategy or a
specific approach on how to completely
avoid a liquidity sweep or these massive
wick outs that are seen right here in
the market or anticipate this liquidity
spike that comes into the market is 100%
lying to you. There is no way that you
can anticipate for a move like this to
happen. There's no way that you can
have a specific strategy to trade solely
off of these sweeps. Can you catch a
couple of them here and there? Sure. Can
you get lucky where you avoid some of
them here and there? Sure. But there's
no consistency in something that trading
is already random as it is. It's going
to either go up or down. Now, if you're
going to make a decision that it's going
to go down, why would you wait for a
confirmation for it to go up first then
before going down? That just logically
doesn't make any sense to me. You want
to look for every possible reason for it
to continue to go down. So, the way that
I use liquidity sweeps in my favor to
enter a position or these liquidity
grabs is by simply not paying any mind
to it. I go enter a position when I have
a confirmation. So, this is very simple.
Waiting for a liquidity sweep to enter a
position is almost like playing defense
in trading. And waiting for a
confirmation in trading to enter the
position is playing offense. We're going
in the favor. If I'm looking to sell a
market, for example,
let's say this same exact example right
here. AUD/CHF. Let's say I'm looking to
sell this market right here.
I am not going and like let's do this
before I even enter the position. I am
not going to be interested in selling
this market once I have a move happen
opposite of what I'm interested in
looking for. If I'm looking to sell this
market, I want to look for every
possible reason to sell. If there's a
move that happens against my sell
position, I'm not going to be interested
in selling because it's clearly not
going in my favor. No given point am I
going to anticipate that that's going to
be a liquidity sweep or that's going to
be a liquidity grab. Why anticipate
something when trading is already enough
anticipation as it is? So, why am I
going to anticipate something that is
against my trade
to enter the trade in the direction that
I want to go. If I want to sell and it's
giving me buy indications, why would I
like to sell? Makes no sense. So, in
this example, we're heading to the
upside. Many would look to call this a
liquidity sweep. And the reason why I
think people do this, and I think this
is a psychological
shift that traders have shifted as years
have turned by and they've normalized
it, and I think that it's actually
making the trader take more steps back
in their journey rather than forward,
is they didn't get their specific
entry confirmation. They're saying
they're looking for bearish
confirmation. They didn't get that
confirmation at that given point. Now,
they're finding a reason still to enter
the trade off of this having a bullish
push to the upside, and they're calling
it a potential liquidity sweep. So,
they're entering the trade on an
anticipation, and not a real
confirmation. So, this right here could
be a liquidity sweep, but you're
anticipating for it to be a liquidity
sweep where it that this make that that
makes no sense. Why would you enter off
of it on anticipation? You want to enter
on a confirmation. What would a
confirmation be like? Okay, it rejected.
Now that this rejected this resistance
that I'm looking to sell, I want a
confirmation
that it's actually going to the
downside. Which what would be a
confirmation? A bearish candlestick
confirming that it's going in that
direction. So, I am not trading on the
anticipation that this could potentially
be that move. No, I did this could have
had five bullish candlesticks that
closed up here. Until I didn't get my
bearish candlesticks, I was not
interested in entering the position.
Because those bullish candlesticks could
have just continued to be the bullish
push to the upside. And then traders out
there would go ahead and lose the
position and be like, "Well, why am I
losing a position uh you know, this
wasn't the liquidity sweeper this you
know, didn't have the move that I
expected." Yeah.
You're not entering on any confirmation.
You're entering purely on anticipation
from the market. And that by itself, if
you shift that approach to the market,
you're going to realize that you're
going to stop chasing these trades and
making them seem something like they're
not, and you're simply going to be very
patient and wait for the trades that are
giving you the correct confirmations.
Might take a little bit longer, might
have to be a little bit more patient,
but patience pays once you're on this
side of the table. And to be completely
honest, it probably took me 2 and 1/2
years to really understand this and
about another year to actually perfect
it. At this point in my journey, I still
make mistakes where I still enter trades
on anticipations, but I know exactly
what I'm doing. I know I'm entering a
trade on anticipation and I'm totally
okay with the outcome. The trade could
go straight to my stop loss and it won't
matter to me. The problem with 99% of
traders is that they enter these
positions, they don't know the type of
positions they're entering, they're not
okay with the risk, and then when they
lose a position, they
go and point the finger at someone else.
Not only do they have the wrong
reasoning to enter the trade, not only
do they not even know why they're
entering the trade, but then they're
putting the blame on anybody but their
but themselves. So, I'm going to give
you right now a very simple breakdown
how to use this liquidity in your
advantage. Market moves very simple, as
many of you guys already know. You guys
should have some type of experience in
the markets. You know, the market moves
in highs and lows. When a market is at a
high point, you don't want to buy at the
high point. It's like buying Bitcoin
once it's hit the highest point it's
been. Why do you want to be that person?
You're late into the move. Wait for the
market to give a little bit of that
discount. That discount is where the
sellers are going to come in, they're
going to liquidate their positions, and
that's where you're going to get your
opportunity. You never want to buy at
the most expensive point or at the high.
That's too much anticipation for it to
go to continuously the next high. So,
you wait for this bit of a retracement,
wait for some people to liquidate their
positions, and that's where then you
will find yourself to have a liquidity
zone, an area of interest, support or
resistance, supply and demand zone,
potato potato, whatever you want to call
it. You want to make sure that there is
a track record of multiple times that
the market has rejected from that area,
that there is liquidity at that zone.
Very simple to what this zone is.
Whenever you're above this area, it goes
up. You just want to
buy it again if it's above it. It's very
simple. Next thing that you want to do
is wait for a confirmation.
Don't wait for a liquidity sweep.
Don't anticipate that the market is
going to do something like this because
what will end up happening is that this
market will then have the push to the
upside and then you're going to be like,
"No, you know what? That's a good
confirmation, but I'm going to wait for
it to have the fake out, for it to have
the liquidity sweep, and then I'll enter
the position after." I hope you realize
if you would have done that specifically
just for this market right here every
single time it approached this area. One
time,
two times,
three times,
four times,
right here,
three times,
four times,
five times,
six times,
and seven times right here. One time
would you have only gotten the liquidity
grab?
Is it worth waiting for this liquidity
grab to happen and miss out on every
single one of these opportunities? Look
at this beautiful confirmation that we
are actually rejecting this area.
Bullish engulfing candlestick. Boom.
Could have bought in just off of that
alone. You have the confirmation. You
have the
push of the market going in that favor,
but you believe that the market was
going to give you a liquidity sweep, and
then you miss out on this position. Same
exact thing happened again. Morning star
bullish engulfing confirmation, you miss
out on this position. Bullish candle
rejection, you miss out on this push to
the upside. Bullish pin bar rejection,
you miss out on this push to the upside.
Don't trade playing defense waiting for
this to happen every single time. You're
going to drive yourself crazy. You're
going to miss out on so many
opportunities. If price has come into
this area and it's giving you your
confirmation that it's going in the
direction that you're anticipating for
it to go. You have all the liquidity in
your favor to continue buying in that
direction. So, just enter the trade. You
cannot avoid for these liquidity moves,
these liquidity fake outs to happen.
It's impossible. Save yourself the
headache. It makes no sense to just have
that in the back of your mind. Will this
happen to you and you will get caught at
times? Yes. And you will continuously to
do that as you go through your trading
journey. There's no way to avoid it.
Myself, that I've been doing this for
the last 7 years, happens to me every
single time and it can happen once uh
every 2 weeks. All I do is just take the
next trade and wait for the next
approach. I don't let it affect my next
trade. And this is probably the most
important thing that I break down with
my students every single Sunday. I get
on a call every single Sunday with my
students on Sunday Swings and I break
down to them the top six, eight, nine,
10 pairs that I'm trading for that week
ahead. I give them the specific markets
that have the best amount of liquidity,
the best buying power, and why it should
go in one direction versus the other.
And the beauty of this is that we have
weekly calls where I break down the
reasonings as to why it should continue
to go in that direction. I review their
trade setups. There's a community aspect
where you can engage with other traders,
and we break this down every single day.
And the biggest turning point for all of
my students is trading on confirmation,
not on anticipation. You want to make
sure you have as many possible
confirmations to have that trade
continuously go in your direction. You
guys want to know more about my
community, get on calls with me every
single Sunday, DM me the word Sunday
Swings, click the link down below, shoot
me a DM. I'll personally reply to you
and see if you're a right fit for our
university where we're training traders
every single week to have the exact same
results that I personally do by live
trading, reviewing their trades, and
most importantly giving them a strategy
that works and that has success every
single week. Hope you guys enjoyed this
video. Make sure to hit that like and
subscribe button and DM me the word
Sunday Swings. See you guys in the next
video.